Guide to the Records of the Peace Corps Training Program RISM.RG.6
New York University Archives
- Series VII. Teaching Papers
  - Subseries D. Health Education
    - Correspondence, Peace Corps health and training course [Oct 1961], 1962 March-April (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, notes, agenda for nurse-health education, 1962 March-May (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, medical kit list, instructions for use of medications, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - List of articles and books for health and medical training course, pamphlet Health Hints for the Tropics, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Subseries E. Physical Education
    - Correspondence, notes, ephemera, 1962 March-April (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Instructions for playing cricket, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Article, ephemera, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Physical fitness index scores; grade scores, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series VIII. Field Trips and Special Events
  8 folders, arranged chronologically. This series documents the various field trips and extra-curricular activities organized on behalf of the Peace Corps volunteers. Highlights of this series include correspondence between Dr. Rubin and Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt regarding a visit to Hyde Park, letters to Adelai Stevenson, at the United Nations, and the volunteers visit to highly publicized birthday rally held for President John F. Kennedy at Madison Square Garden in New York City. Volunteers also visited major libraries, the New Jersey Department of Labor and Agriculture, and toured Washington, D.C.
  - Field trip schedules and agendas, 1962 March-April (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence related to Hyde Park visit, 1962 March-April (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence for United Nations visit, 1962 March-April (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, agenda for Washington, D.C. tour, 1962 April (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence National Arts Club, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Radio Music City Hall, 1962 April-May (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, agenda for visit to N.J. Dept. of Labor and Agriculture, notes, 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Annual Dance, Caribbean Federation for Mental Health, 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and agenda for various library visits, 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, ticket for Madison Square Birthday Rally held for President John F. Kennedy, 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Agenda, brochure on West Indian dance, notes, 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Directions to Manhattan sites, visitors guide, Columbia University Student Handbook, miscellaneous papers, 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Series IX. Volunteer Files [RESTRICTED]
  1.0 linear feet (2 boxes) arranged alphabetically. This is a restricted series that contains individual volunteer files consisting of biographical data, self-evaluation inventories, confidential reports, test booklets, personal interviews, profile and case summaries, test scores, assessment summaries, and essays. There are also volunteer evaluations of the Peace Corps Training Program.
- Series X. Volunteer Placement Records
  Approximately .75 linear feet (1 box), arranged chronologically. This series documents volunteer placement by region and area of study, selective service status where applicable, and other items effecting their assignments. Also included are numerous forms issued by the Peace Corps, correspondence, memorandum, passport and visa applications and instructions, suggestions for clothing and miscellaneous papers.
  - Report of Final Selection Board forms, volunteer placement lists by region and area of study, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Office of Selection, volunteer placement lists by region; volunteer lists, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum Concerning [Military] Selective Service and Reserve Obligations, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum on Moratorium for National Defense Student Loans, Selective Service Status of Volunteers forms, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Peer Nomination Forms, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, clothing suggestions for Jamaica, W.I., 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Clothing suggestions for Peace Corp Projects in Brazil and El Salvador, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Abstract on transistor radios, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Information for Jamaican, W.I. visas, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Passport Application forms and instructions, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Instructions, Notice of Termination of Volunteer in Training forms, notes, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Instructions and Application to Withdraw Termination Payments, notes, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Memorandum, forms and correspondence concerning to departure and home leave, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Volunteer shipping requests, notes, 1962 May (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Series XI. Photographs
  1 vol., contents arranged alphabetically by volunteer's last name. The binder contains original and Xeroxed group photos (8 x 10). Two photographs (5 x 7) of each volunteer are consecutively numbered and lettered "a" and "b." The binder also contains a photograph of Herbert L. Wright, Youth Secretary of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. Wright was one of several lecturers for the Area Studies component of the Peace Corps Training Program. Invoices, notes and miscellaneous papers related to the photographs are also included.
  - Peace Corps Group Photograph taken by Alex Aster [original], 1962 April-May (Box 13a)
  - Peace Corps Group Photograph [photocopy], 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder Grp p/c)
  - Braidic, Anthony, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 1 a/b)
  - Brunelli, Roger, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 2 a/b)
  - Bryan, Sam, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 3 a/b)
  - Case, Charles, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 4 a/b)
  - Cornelius, Lloyd, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 5 a/b)
  - Doherty, James, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 6 a/b)
  - Duba, Betty, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 7 a/b)
  - Earnshaw, Janet, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 8 a/b)
  - Garner, Johnnie, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 9 a/b)
  - Gibbs, Kenneth, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 10 a/b)
  - Grobe, Richard, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 11 a/b)
  - Grobe, Ruby, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 12 a/b)
  - Harris, Daniel, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 13 a/b)
  - Harvey, John, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 14 a/b)
  - Henderson, John, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 15 a/b)
  - House, Hugh, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 16 a/b)
  - Hughes, Barbara F., 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 17 a/b)
  - Jones, Anthony, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 18 a/b)
  - Kite, Kenneth, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 19 a/b)
  - Lathan, Thoyd, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 20 a/b)
  - Ludin, Philip, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 21 a/b)
  - Mayeda, Yutaka, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 22 a/b)
  - Murphy, Joseph, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 23 a/b)
  - Nolting, Barbara, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 24 a/b)
  - O'Brien, Robert, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 25 a/b)
  - Quanbeck, Fay, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 26 a/b)
  - Ragsdale, Robert, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 27 a/b)
  - Ragsdale, Winifred, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 28 a/b)
  - Robertson, William, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 29 a/b)
  - Ross, Robert, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 30 a/b)
  - Schnebel, Carol, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 31 a/b)
  - Sharman, Benjamin, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 32 a/b)
  - Smith, Marvin, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 33 a/b)
  - Smith, Virginia, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 34 a/b)
  - Tanaka, Elsie, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 35 a/b)
  - Villicana, Rita, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 36 a/b)
  - Vincent, Walter, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 37 a/b)
  - Vogel, Arnold, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 38 a/b)
  - Williams, William M., 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 39 a/b)
  - Wilmoth, Stephen, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 40 a/b)
  - Young, Pauline, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 41 a/b)
  - Wright, Herbert L., Youth Secretary, NAACP [See box 11, folder 45, 1962 April-May (Box 13a, Folder 42)
- Series XII. Public Relations
  6 folders, arranged chronologically. The papers in this series were created to promote the Peace Corps Training Program. Included are press releases, correspondence announcements, media interviews and broadcasts. See also Series XIV. Audiovisual Materials.
  - Draft copy, press release announcement of Jamaica Peace Corps Training Program, 1962 April-May (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Press Release announcement, 1962 March-April (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Press Release announcement (revised), 1962 March-April (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, notes regarding volunteer radio and television interviews, 1962 April-June (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - List of radio and television and coverage of the program in New York, draft statement describing press coverage in the Jamaica Daily Gleaner and the Peace Corps Training graduation ceremonies described in the New York Times, 1962 May-June (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Announcement of Peace Corps Training Program graduation broadcast on The Listener's Digest, WRUL, 1962 May-June (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Series XIII. Clippings
  Approximately 2.0 linear feet (2 boxes), contents arranged chronologically. This series is comprised of newspaper clippings. Although some clippings relate to the Peace Corps Program and its volunteers, other clippings describe issues in the Caribbean, the U.S. Civil Rights movement, and communism, some of which were most likely used in teaching. Additional clippings are included under Series XIV. Oversized Materials
  - "Jersey Aid Given to Virgin Islands," N.Y. Times, 1962 February (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "...Give U.N. Data on Glenn..." N.Y. Times, 1962 February (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "Tyro Stylist from Japan Aids Expert," N.Y. Times, 1962 February (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Peace Corps Praised," N.Y. Times, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "New Methods Aired by Science Teachers," N.Y. Times, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - "Sit-Ins Examined by Philosopher," N.Y. Times, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Communists Using Peace Corps Title," N.Y. Times, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Peace Corps Unit On Island Lauded," N.Y. Times, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "Sugar Workers Rebel," N.Y. Times" [?], 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "The Peace Corps -- A Year Later," N.Y. Post, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "TV: Preview of International Affairs," N.Y. Times, 1962 March (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - "U.S. Asked to Spur Behavior Studies," N.Y. Times, 1962 April (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - "New West Indies Tie Proposed by Britain," N.Y. Times, 1962 April (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "It's Left Vs. Left In Jamaica," The Arizona Republic, 1962 April (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - "An American's Impression of Cricket," [Unknown source], 1962 April (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "Peace Corps Training Record," [Unknown source], 1962 April (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - "The Peaceless Corps," The Daily News, 1962 May (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - "40 Peace Corps Trainees To Be Graduated Here," N.Y. Times, 1962 May (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - "Kennedy Sees Corps Training Diplomats," N.Y. Times, 1962 June (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - "David Muholland, Member of Peace Corps, Dies at 23," N.Y. Times, 1962 June (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - "Peace Corps Offers Help for Dominica," Dominica Herald, 1962 August (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - ""Peace Corps Unit to Train Here," N.Y. Daily News" [?], 1962 September (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - "80 Peace Corpsmen Due in City Oct 6 For Work in Slums," N.Y. Times, 1962 September (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - "Peace Corps Trains in New York," N.Y. Times Magazine, 1962 October (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - "Peace Corps Men in Jamaica Feel Their Skills Are Wasted," N.Y. Times, 1962 December (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - "Agricultural Aid to Underdeveloped Countries" [partial article] Science, Vol. 134, undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - "New Ways Sought to Rate Students," N.Y. Times, undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - "Puerto Ricans Here Set Up Youth Aid," N.Y. Times, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - "Thank You, Peace Corps," [unknown source], undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - "Puerto Ricans Here Ask Drive to Train Youths for Future," N.Y. Times" [?], undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - "Highlights of the News Back Home," The Jamaica Weekly Gleaner, 1962 March (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Columbia Spectator, 1962 March (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Peace Corps A Thriving Operation as 1,000th Volunteer Heads for Overseas Duty," N.Y. Times, 1962 June (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Series XIV. Maps, oversized illustrations
  1.0 linear feet (1 oversized box). This series contains oversized maps and illustrations, used to support the coursework and technical training taught in the Peace Corps Training Program, particularly area studies, geography and agricultural skills. Some illustrations relate to the volunteers' specific assignments.
  - British Caribbean Colonies, color print map by Leo Vernon, distributed by British Information Services, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Two hand drawn maps of Cousins Cove, Pedro Pen and surrounding area, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Details of regional placement based on map; two survey maps of Jamaica, W.I., undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Illustrations of various canoes, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Illustration of fish pot, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified regional map, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Various road maps of Jamaica, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Peace Corps Newspaper Clippings, Oversized, 1962 June (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Unprocessed maps, 1940-1971 (Flat-file-folder 15, Box Shared University Archives 056, Folder 4)
- Series XV. Audiovisual Materials
  (1 record carton). This series consists of reel-to-reel audio and visual recordings of the Jamaica Peace Corps training activities. The tapes includes lectures, the graduation ceremony, volunteer interviews, and a visit with Mrs. Franklin Roosevelt at Hyde Park, New York. Several recordings in this series, which were transferred to CD/DVD format, have been appended to the collection.
  - Subseries A. General
    - Audio reel 1 of 3 (7.5") of the Language Guide to Jamaica, compiled by Beryl Bailey, 1962 April; cuid10 (Box 17)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original Format: ¼" Open Reel Audio
      Housing Annotations:
      Labeled "Tape A." Reel 1 of 3.
      Duration: 33 Minutes
    - Audio reel 2 of 3 (7.5") of the Language Guide to Jamaica, compiled by Beryl Bailey, 1962 April; cuid400 (Box 17)
    - Audio reel 3 of 3 (7.5") of the Language Guide to Jamaica, compiled by Beryl Bailey, 1962 April; cuid401 (Box 17)
      Duration: 26 minutes
    - Audio reel Tape B (5") of the Language Guide to Jamaica, compiled by Beryl Bailey, 1962 April; cuid402 (Box 17)
      Duration: 104 minutes
    - Audiocassette 1 of 2 of the Jamaican Creole Language Guide, compiled by Beryl Bailey, 1962 April; cuid11 (Box Shared University Archives 098)
    - Audiocassette 2 of 2 of the Jamaican Creole Language Guide, compiled by Beryl Bailey, 1962 April; cuid403 (Box Shared University Archives 098)
      Cassette reads "speech accelerated"
    - 1 film recording of Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt recorded during field trip to Hyde Park, New York, 1962 April; cuid12 (Box 17, Folder N/A)
    - Audio reel 1 of 3 (7.5") of the Peace Corps Jamaica Graduation Ceremonies at Inter-national House. Key note address by Sir Hugh Foot, 1962 May 30; cuid13 (Box 17)
      Duration: 24 minutes
    - Audio reel 2 of 3 (7.5") of the Peace Corps Jamaica Graduation Ceremonies at Inter-national House. Key note address by Sir Hugh Foot, 1962 May 30; cuid404 (Box 17)
      Container reads: "Worldwide Broadcasting A Division of Metropolitan Broadcasting Corporation WRUL International Radio Station 4 West 58th Street New York 19, NY Mitchell Krauss, Director of News"
      "Peace Corps Graduation Address by: Sir Hugh Foot U.K. ambassador to U.N."
      Duration: 35 Minutes
    - Audio reel 3 of 3 (7.5") of the Peace Corps Jamaica Graduation Ceremonies at Inter-national House. Key note address by Sir Hugh Foot, 1962 May 30; cuid405 (Box 17)
      Duration: 28 minutes
    - 1 reel-to-reel tape (5") of Peace Corps volunteers Mr. & Mrs. Robert Ragsdale interview on the Allen Gray Show, WCBS, 1962 May 16; cuid14 (Box 17)
      Duration: 16 Minutes; Preservation Note: Significant speed and wow/flutter issues that are part of the recording itself.
    - 1 reel-to-reel tape (7.5") of Dr. Bert Schaffner lecture: Mental health and Peace Corps volunteers, 1962 May; cuid15 (Box 17)
      Duration: 90 Mintes
    - Film recording of Louise Bennett performance at the Peace Corps graduation ceremony, 1962 May; cuid16 (Box 17, Folder N/A)
    - 1 reel-to-reel tape (7.5") of Vera Rubin and Ms. Lane of the Peace Corps Contracts Div,, Washington, D.C., 1962 May; cuid17 (Box 17)
      Duration: 22 Minutes; Preservation Note: Poor audio quality (Phone conversations)
    - 1 reel-to-reel tape (7.5") Louise Bennett: Jamaica Folklore, 1962 May 28; cuid18 (Box 17)
      Duration: 93 Minutes; Preservation Note: Poor audio quality ("Open air" sound for track 1 and through 00:22:20 of track 2, then very close and muted sound for the remainder of track 2)
  - Subseries B. Appended materials
    - Two compact disc copies of Louise Bennett perforance at the Peace Corps graduation ceremony, undated; cuid19 (Box 17)
- Series XVI. Peace Corps Graduation Ceremony
  .5 linear feet (1 box), arranged chronologically. This series documents the planning activities leading up to the graduation ceremony held for Peace Corps Volunteers. The papers include correspondence, invitations, programs, diplomas and related material.
  - Correspondence, includes telegram from Robert Sargent Shriver, Jr., 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - International House Booking Charge Sheets, stage and seating diagram, notes, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Graduation ceremony invitations, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Graduation programs, notes, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Graduation programs, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Graduation programs, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Graduation programs, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Graduation programs, 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Diplomas [blank], 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Diplomas [blank], 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Diplomas [blank], 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Diplomas [blank], 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Diplomas [void copies not used -- inscribed with volunteer names], 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Diplomas [void copies not used -- inscribed with volunteer names], 1962 May (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Series XVII. Peace Corps Volunteer Publications
  .5 linear feet (1 box), arranged chronologically. This series contains newsletters organized by or published for Peace Corps volunteers. The newsletters provide details of various Peace Corps projects, including the activities of graduates from the Jamaica Peace Corps Training Program.
  - Peace Corps News, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1961 June (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Peace Corps News, Vol. 2, No. 2, 1962 February (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Peace Corps News, Vol. 2, No. 3, 1962 March (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - The Monthly Eye, 1962 April-May (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Monthly Eye, 1962 April-May (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Monthly Eye, 1962 April-May (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Peace Corps News, Vol. 2, No. 4, 1962 May (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Bull Sheet, 1963 March (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Peace Corps Newsletter, 1965 March-April (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Peace Corps in Jamaica, 1982 March (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Peace Corps in Belize, 1982 December (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Series XVIII. Final Reports
  .5 linear feet (1 box), arranged chronologically. This series contains correspondence, draft outlines, grading forms and reports submitted by Program faculty and medical consultants. These reports were incorporated in the final Peace Corps report, also included.
  - Correspondence, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Final grades, grade and evaluation forms, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Physical Education report, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Librarian report, 1962 June-July (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Nurse-Health Education report, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Report of Medical Consultant, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - American and World Affairs report, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Vocational Education report, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Evaluation Officer Report, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - International House Report, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Final Report draft outlines, 1962 June (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Final Report, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Final Report - Appendices, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Final Report - Appendices, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Final Report - Appendices, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Final Report - Appendices, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Final Report - Appendices, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Peace Corps conference agenda, notes, draft material, 1962 June-July (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Series XIV. Miscellaneous Papers
  - Books Related to the Peace Corps, Manuals and Reports for Volunteers, circa 1960s (Box 21)